Come here, girl. Jess, Jess.
过来，姑娘。杰斯，杰斯。
DOG BARKS
狗吠
DOOR CHIMES
门铃
This way, Mrs Brompton.
Thank you.
这边，布朗普顿夫人。
谢谢你。
To what do we owe the pleasure?
我们应该享受什么？
Well, it's that time of year.
嗯，这是一年中的那个时候。
Oh, the Daffodil Ball, I've been
counting the days.
哦，水仙花球，我一直在
数日子。
And who's the lucky lass tonight?
谁是今晚的幸运儿？
Who can say at this point,
Mrs Brompton.
在这一点上谁能说，
布朗普顿夫人。
Ah, Jim, Jim, perfect timing.
Ah, wallet!
啊，钱包！
I'm sorry, what am I paying for now?
对不起，我现在付什么钱？
It's the Daffodil Ball tonight.
今晚是水仙花舞会。
All proceeds go towards the
restoration of the steeple.
所有收益都用于
修复尖塔。
It's the highlight of the social
calendar.
这是社交
日历的亮点。
There'll be music, dancing, the
frisson of a warm spring evening.
会有音乐、舞蹈
和温暖的春夜的颤栗。
Mr Farnon not in?
法农先生不在？
He's yet to grace us
with his presence.
他的存在还没有给我们
带来恩典。
How about it, Mrs Hall, a ticket
for you?
怎么样，霍尔太太，
给你一张票？
Just four, please. Four?
请只给四个。四？
Yeah, need one for my date
for the evening.
是的，我
晚上的约会需要一个。
Your date?
你的约会？
The day is young.
天还年轻。
Come on, Jim, no girl likes a
cheapskate.
来吧，吉姆，没有女孩喜欢
小气鬼。
Who's the extra one for?
Who do you think?
多给谁？
你认为是谁？
Time waits for no man, Jim lad, and
neither will Helen.
时间不等人，吉姆小伙子，
海伦也不会。
Morning, Mrs Brompton.
早上好，布朗普顿夫人。
Diana - please.
戴安娜 - 请。
How can we be of service?
我们如何为您服务？
Daffodil Ball.
水仙球。
If you're not too busy I wondered
如果你不是太忙，我想
if we might lure you on to the dance
floor.
如果我们可以引诱你到舞池
。
Well, that depends what you're using
as bait.
嗯，这取决于你用什么
作为诱饵。
SHE GIGGLES
她咯咯地笑
Stop it.
停下来。
It would be our pleasure to
support the cause.
我们很高兴
支持这项事业。
Tristan, money? Yeah.
特里斯坦，钱？是的。
"Our pleasure" really?
“我们的快乐”真的吗？
And, uh, Mrs Hall, would you mind
showing Diana out?
而且，呃，霍尔夫人，你介意把
戴安娜带出去吗？
Show her out?
给她看？
We'll have to scrape her off him
first.
我们得先把她从他身上刮下来
。
This way.
这边走。
Swap. Thank you. Thank you,
bye-bye...
交换。谢谢你。谢谢，
再见……
What?
什么？
What, is it?
它是什么？
I mean, if you can't see, then
我的意思是，如果你看不到，那么
there's really no hope for you,
brother.
你真的没有希望了，
兄弟。
If that woman were any more forward,
she'd be here yesterday.
如果那个女人再向前，
她昨天就会在这里。
Nonsense, Diana's happily married.
废话，戴安娜的婚姻美满。
Isn't she?
她不是吗？
Not any longer. Not for a year now.
没有了。现在不是一年。
Well, she was probably just
being friendly.
好吧，她可能只是
出于友好。
You know, I heard he ran off with
the housekeeper.
你知道，我听说他和
管家跑了。
I heard the gardener.
我听到了园丁的声音。
How did you get on with Merrick last
night?
昨晚你和梅里克相处得怎么样？
I thought you were going to tag
that on to the end of your list.
我以为你会把它标记
到你的清单的末尾。
Oh, James, you really can't allow
yourself to be so forgetful.
哦，詹姆斯，你真的不能让
自己这么健忘。
The memory is a muscle that must be
exercised.
记忆力是一块必须
锻炼的肌肉。
I'll get up there right away.
我马上上去。
No, no, you've got a busy surgery
today.
不，不，你
今天的手术很忙。
Here.
这里。
Organised as ever.
一如既往地组织起来。
Why doesn't Tristan stay
and help out?
为什么特里斯坦不留下来
帮忙？
With both examination rooms
in operation,
随着两间考场
的运作，
we'd get through them a lot quicker.
我们会更快地通过它们。
I'd like to keep Tristan under my
wing for a while.
我想让特里斯坦在我的保护下
一段时间。
He's still got a lot to learn.
他还有很多东西要学。
Go on, go and get ready.
来吧，去准备吧。
Mr Farnon - postcard from Dorothy.
法农先生 - 来自多萝西的明信片。
Who's the old Siegfried?
谁是老齐格弗里德？
And why does she hope he gets out
from time to time?
而她为什么希望他
时不时地出去？
Sorry, I thought it were for me.
对不起，我以为是给我的。
I didn't realise until it were too
late.
我没有意识到，直到为时已
晚。
I'm sure.
我确定。
HORN BLARES
喇叭喇叭
All right, all right, I'm coming.
好了好了，我来了。
No Rover? Not today, it's leaking
oil everywhere.
没有路虎？不是今天，
到处都是漏油。
Do your tie up, man, we must present
our very best self to our clients.
做好准备，伙计，我们必须
向客户展示我们最好的自己。
You know, you could do far worse
than Diana Brompton.
你知道，你可以做得
比戴安娜布朗普顿差得多。
I see you got another postcard from
Dorothy.
我看到你收到
多萝西寄来的另一张明信片。
How's Malta?
马耳他怎么样？
Hot and rocky.
炎热而崎岖。
She's looking forward to becoming a
grandmother.
她期待着成为
祖母。
Shame, I got the impression you were
rather fond of her.
不好意思，我感觉你
挺喜欢她的。
Oh, hang on, hang on, slow down,
slow down.
哦，坚持，坚持，慢下来，
慢下来。
Stop.
停止。
Morning, Helen.
早上好，海伦。
All right, Triss, Siegfried.
好的，特莉丝，齐格弗里德。
What can I do for you?
我能为你做什么？
Oh, it's not me, actually.
哦，其实不是我。
Um, I think James wanted to see
you about something.
嗯，我想詹姆斯想见
你谈一些事情。
He's at the house if you wanted to
pop in.
如果你想
进来，他就在家里。
Right.
对。
Thanks.
谢谢。
Bye. BOTH: Bye.
再见。双方：再见。
Helen. Hello.
海伦。你好。
Please, come in, come in.
请进，进。
Come on through.
来吧。
There we are.
我们到了。
OK, then...
好吧...
..how can I help?
..我能帮忙吗？
I thought you wanted to see me.
我以为你想见我。
You did? I mean, I do. Why wouldn't
I?
你做到了吗？我的意思是，我愿意。我为什么不
呢？
Of course I'd like to see you...
我当然想见你...
Right.
对。
Only, I've got to get back and put
our carrots in, so, shall we?
只是，我得回去把
我们的胡萝卜放进去，所以，我们可以吗？
Sorry, shall we what?
对不起，我们怎么办？
The reason you wanted to see me.
你想见我的原因。
I'm not sure I understand -
you came here.
我不确定我是否理解 -
你来过这里。
Because Tristan asked me to.
因为特里斯坦让我这么做。
Ah.
啊。
He said you wanted to speak to me
about something.
他说你想和我
谈谈一些事情。
I'm sure he did.
我确定他做到了。
Well...
好...
Triss and I are going to the
Daffodil Ball.
特莉丝和我要去
水仙花舞会。
And I couldn't be happier for you.
我为你感到高兴。
Oh, no, no, he's not...
Not together.
哦，不，不，他没有……
没有在一起。
I mean, well, we are but not...
我的意思是，我们是，但不是……
James, it's fine...
詹姆斯，没关系……
..you have my blessings.
..你有我的祝福。
See, because of that...
看，正因为如此……
..now I'm not inviting you.
..现在我不是在邀请你。
I had a spare ticket but I'll just
have to give it to someone else.
我有一张备用票，但我必须
把它给别人。
Probably for the best.
可能是最好的。
I haven't really been out since...
自从我真的没有出去...
..well...
..好...
No-one will care.
没有人会在意。
We'll go as a group, you, me,
Triss...
我们一起去，你，我，
特莉丝……
..whoever he manages to drag along.
..无论他设法拖着谁。
I'm a terrible dancer,
我是一个糟糕的舞者，
so that amusement alone is a good
enough reason to come.
因此，仅娱乐就
足以成为您来的理由。
I don't know.
我不知道。
DOOR CHIMES
门铃
It's my dog.
是我的狗
He disappeared yesterday
evening on one of our walks.
他昨天
晚上在我们的一次散步中失踪了。
I found him when I went back out
again this morning,
今天早上我再出去的时候发现了他，
he must've been in this
trap all night.
他一定
整晚都在这个圈套里。
Well, bring him through.
好吧，带他过去。
James!
詹姆士！
DOG WHINES
狗叫声
I need you!
我需要你！
Don't worry, go.
别着急，走吧。
We need to get him something for the
pain and sedated right away.
我们需要给他一些
止痛药并立即镇静。
What's his name? It's Rock.
他的名字是什么？是摇滚。
Mrs Hall, pass the cotton wool,
please.
霍尔太太，
请把棉线递过去。
You'll be able to save him,
won't you?
你一定能救他的，
不是吗？
I can't tell.
我说不清。
I won't be able to tell you
until I've explored the wound.
在我探查伤口之前，我无法告诉你。
Who would do such a thing?
谁会做这种事？
It's monstrous.
太可怕了。
Oh, it looks a mess.
哦，看起来一团糟。
I won't know until I'm right
inside how bad it is.
我不会知道，直到我就
在里面，它有多糟糕。
What I'd do for an X-ray machine
now.
我现在会为 X 光机做些什么
。
Doesn't seem natural, being able to
看起来不自然，能够
see your insides on the outside like
that.
像
这样在外面看到你的内在。
They're an incredible diagnostic
tool.
它们是令人难以置信的诊断
工具。
All right, he's asleep.
好吧，他睡着了。
I don't think the leg's broken.
我不认为腿断了。
We better hope there's still some
circulation to the paw.
我们最好希望
爪子还有一些循环。
And if there's not?
如果没有？
I'm afraid he'll lose the foot.
我怕他会失去一只脚。
Colonel, good morning.
上校，早上好。
Now, then, Farnon, what's all this
about?
那么，法农，这到底是怎么回事
？
We were expecting you last night.
昨晚我们在等你。
Yeah, I'm afraid, there was
something
是的，我害怕，有
什么事
of an administrative balls up.
的行政球了。
My colleague missed you off his
list.
我的同事想念你的
名单。
Oh, and there I was believing I was
one of your most valued clients.
哦，在那里我相信我是
你最重要的客户之一。
Oh, I'm almost hurt.
哦，我快受伤了。
Rest assured, you have my undivided
attention now.
请放心，您
现在得到了我的全神贯注。
Bag please, Tristan.
请提包，特里斯坦。
Yes, err, unfortunately, I've
是的，错误，不幸的是，我已经
had to find another dance partner.
不得不另找舞伴。
Sorry to say, too little, too late,
old chap.
对不起，太少了，太晚了，
老家伙。
Still, there's, there's nothing like
a bit of healthy
尽管如此，没有什么
比健康更重要的了
competition to keep you on your
toes, hey, Farnon?
竞争让你保持
警觉，嘿，法农？
Indeed.
的确。
George, what a qualified pleasure it
is to see you.
乔治，
见到你真是太高兴了。
HE LAUGHS
他笑了
Now, now, chaps, we mustn't
squabble.
现在，现在，伙计们，我们不能
争吵。
I'd hate to be the bone between a
pair of scrapping dogs.
我不想成为一
对废狗之间的骨头。
If you're finding yourself
unable to cope,
如果你发现自己
无法应付，
I could always take a few more
clients off your hands.
我总能从
你手中夺走更多的客户。
I'm perfectly capa... More than
capable, thank you.
我完全有
能力...不仅仅是有能力，谢谢。
Oh, there's no shame in admitting
you can't keep up.
哦，承认
你跟不上，并不可耻。
The years are rolling on.
岁月在流转。
Ha-ha, the coup de grace.
哈哈，致命一击。
Until next time, Hubert.
直到下一次，休伯特。
Rolling on? You're rolling on.
滚？你继续前进。
He's older than I am.
他比我大。
Still, since you've come all this
way,
不过既然你这么过来了
，
there's no harm in you casting
an expert eye over her.
你
对她投以专家的眼光没有坏处。
I imagine there wouldn't be a
我想不会有
charge - on account of all the
bother.
收费 - 考虑到所有的
麻烦。
No, of course not, Hubert...
不，当然不是，休伯特……
..anything for our most valued
customer.
..为我们最重要的
客户提供任何服务。
I've asked this morning's clients to
come back this afternoon.
我已经请今天上午的客户
今天下午回来。
I don't understand why Siegfried
doesn't let Tristan run surgery.
我不明白为什么齐格弗里德
不让特里斯坦做手术。
If there were two of us, we wouldn't
have to send anyone away.
如果我们有两个人，我们就不用
派人离开了。
Mr Farnon has his ways...
法农先生有他的方式......
..maddening as they might be.
..令人抓狂。
It's best to let sleeping dogs lie.
Mm.
最好让熟睡的狗撒谎。
毫米。
I'm not sure I'd describe Siegfried
as a sleeping dog.
我不确定我是否会将齐格弗里德描述
为一只熟睡的狗。
Thanks.
谢谢。
How's he getting on?
他过得怎么样？
I'd like to be able to give
Mr Hammond some good news.
我想告诉
哈蒙德先生一些好消息。
I don't think the bone is broken.
我不认为骨头坏了。
We need to hope it's not infected.
我们需要希望它没有被感染。
Seems like a nice chap.
看起来是个不错的家伙。
He does.
他是这样的。
He is.
他是。
I better get a brew on before he
wears a hole in the floor.
我最好在他
在地板上穿一个洞之前喝一杯。
I'll do the best I can.
我会尽我所能。
102.5.
Stethoscope.
听诊器。
Thank you, Tristan.
谢谢你，特里斯坦。
Pandhi said her insides are blocked
up,
潘迪说她的内脏被堵住
了，
gave her some linseed oil to
grease the wheels.
给了她一些亚麻籽油来
润滑车轮。
Really?
真的吗？
Well, that's one way of doing it,
I suppose.
嗯，
我想这是一种方法。
And that's not the treatment you'd
prescribe?
这不是你
开的治疗方法？
Well, we all have our different
approaches, Colonel.
好吧，我们都有不同的
方法，上校。
And different degrees of success
that go with them.
以及
随之而来的不同程度的成功。
COW MOOS
牛摩丝
Yes, I thought so.
是的，我是这么想的。
You're struggling, aren't you, old
girl?
你在挣扎，是不是，
老姑娘？
Stomach powders. Coming right up.
胃粉。马上就来。
I'm afraid there's definitely
a blockage.
恐怕肯定
有堵塞。
It could be she's had too much
roughage and that's bunged
可能是她吃的
粗粮太多了
her up or there could be a wire or
something else caught up inside.
或者里面可能有电线或
其他东西。
Well, it sounds serious.
嗯，听起来很严重。
More common than you'd think.
比你想象的更常见。
Did Pandhi not mention the
possibility?
潘迪没有提到这种
可能性吗？
I told my stock man to wait for you,
Farnon.
我告诉我的
经纪人等你，法农。
Lesson learned.
学过的知识。
We'll start off with the powders to
help her work it through and
我们将从粉末开始
帮助她完成它
if that doesn't shift it, I'm afraid
we'll have to come back and operate.
如果那不能改变它，恐怕
我们将不得不回来操作。
COW MOOS
牛摩丝
Mr Hammond?
哈蒙德先生？
Oh, noticed the timing's off.
哦，注意到时间不对了。
Well, I put it forward every
morning.
嗯，我每天
早上都提出来。
Well, I could fix it for you, if you
like?
好吧，如果你
愿意，我可以帮你修好？
Oh, I've got used to it now.
哦，我现在已经习惯了。
Sometimes I put it forward more
than I should
有时我
比我应该提出的更多
to get them out the house sooner.
让他们早点离开家。
Well...
好...
..there speaks a woman wise to the
world.
..有一个女人对
世界说话。
Wise to the lot I've been lumbered
with, certainly.
当然，对于我一直困扰的很多事情是明智的
。
Sorry, I've never been good at
waiting for news,
对不起，我一直不擅长
等待消息，
I have to keep myself busy.
我得让自己忙起来。
You and me both.
你和我都。
Mr Herriot is a wonderful vet.
Herriot 先生是一位出色的兽医。
If you want any more milk, you just
let me know.
如果你想要更多的牛奶，你就
告诉我。
I will.
我会。
I'm sorry, in the rush,
I didn't catch your name.
抱歉，匆匆忙忙，
没听清你的名字。
It's...
它的...
..Audrey.
..奥黛丽。
Gerald.
杰拉德。
Sugar, I forgot the sugar.
糖，我忘了糖。
I'll just, um.
我只是，嗯。
No, no, I can leave that.
不，不，我可以离开那个。
And I'll come back with your, uh...
我会和你一起回来，呃...
..with the, um... Sugar.
..与，嗯......糖。
That's the chap.
那是章。
What's this? It's the list.
这是什么？这是清单。
The list, man. Don't look like that,
tell me what's next. Oh.
名单，伙计。不要看起来那样，
告诉我接下来要做什么。哦。
Mr Dinsdale.
丁斯代尔先生。
Ah, yes, sow, aural haematoma.
啊，是的，母猪，耳朵血肿。
See? All up here.
看？都在这
Why would you have Merrick
written twice?
你为什么要让梅里克
写两遍？
Well, I wouldn't.
好吧，我不会。
Unless this was left in your pocket
from last night.
除非这是
昨晚留在你口袋里的。
Which would suggest you were
supposed
这表明你
应该
to go to Merrick's and not James?
去梅里克而不是詹姆斯？
What're you doing?
你在做什么？
We must present our best self for
the clients, Siegfried.
我们必须
向客户展示最好的自己，齐格弗里德。
Morning.
早晨。
Oh, we thought it'd be a grand
adventure...
哦，我们认为这将是一次伟大的
冒险......
..too young to know any better.
..太年轻了，不知道更好。
You were in good company.
你们相处得很好。
I should never have been there in
the first place,
我一开始就不应该去那里
，
I lied to the recruiting officer
about my age.
我向招聘官谎报了
我的年龄。
Oh, God, you were one of those...
哦，上帝，你就是其中之一……
..king, country.
..国王，国家。
The usual nonsense.
平常的废话。
You know, funny thing is...
你知道，有趣的是...
..I wouldn't change it for the
world.
..我不会为这个
世界改变它。
Even though it left me hobbling
about.
尽管它让我蹒跚而行
。
The struggle makes everything all
the more worth it.
奋斗让一切都
变得更值得。
I'll keep telling myself that.
我会一直这样告诉自己。
Mr Hammond, you can come through.
哈蒙德先生，你可以通过。
Thank you for the tea.
谢谢你的茶。
We've patched him up.
我们已经修补了他。
I'm worried there could be an
infection,
好担心会不会
感染
the wound must've been open for some
time.
伤口肯定已经开放了一段
时间。
If it spreads, it could poison the
blood stream.
如果它扩散，它可能毒害
血液。
And then what?
然后什么？
There's still a chance he could lose
the leg.
他仍然有可能失去
这条腿。
Hm, better that than his life.
嗯，比他的命还好。
Leave him with us for a few days.
把他留在我们身边几天。
Hey, you'll be all right, Rock, lad.
嘿，你会没事的，洛克，小伙子。
This nice gentleman and kind lady
are going to take care of you.
这位善良的绅士和善良的女士
会照顾你。
And Jess will keep him company.
Jess 会陪着他。
Will we be seeing you at the dance
then?
那我们会在舞会上见到你
吗？
God willing.
天意。
So long as you fulfil your
professional obligations first.
只要你先履行你的
职业义务。
And, by God, I naturally mean my
brother.
而且，上帝，我自然是指我的
兄弟。
Them eggs will not collect
themselves, you know.
他们的鸡蛋不会
自己收集，你知道。
Should have kept her locked in
the coal shed.
应该把她锁在
煤棚里。
Our little Buttercup's in here.
我们的小毛毛在这里。
Now, that boil on her noggin's even
bigger than last time you were up.
现在，她头上的沸腾
比你上次起床时还要大。
I didn't have the correct instrument
to complete the procedure.
我没有正确的仪器
来完成这个程序。
Here's our little lass now.
现在是我们的小姑娘了。
Holy Mary, Mother of God.
圣母玛利亚，天主之母。
Oh, yes ,I can see from here the
haematoma's even more engorged.
哦，是的，我从这里可以看到
血肿更加充血了。
Ah, looks fit to burst.
啊，看来要炸了。
I thought about going in and having
a go myself, like...
我想
自己进去试一试，就像......
..not for very long, mind.
..不要太久，介意。
Yes, well, it's becoming apparent to
me
是的，这对
我来说变得很明显
now why you might have left your
scalpel at home last time.
现在为什么你
上次可能把手术刀留在家里了。
Thankfully, I believe we have it
here today. Mm.
谢天谢地，我相信我们
今天在这里。毫米。
I don't know why you're
handing that to me,
我不知道你为什么
把它交给我，
we learn by doing, little brother.
我们边做边学，小兄弟。
I imagine she's called Buttercup
because uh...
我想她被称为毛茛
是因为呃...
..well, despite appearances, she's
a tender and sweet soul at heart?
..嗯，尽管外表，她内心深处是
一个温柔甜美的灵魂？
Not as it goes.
不是这样。
Nearly took me finger off once.
有一次差点把我的手指拿开。
If she gets hold of you, my advice
is to play dead.
如果她抓住你，我的建议
是装死。
Unless you think she might actually
kill you,
除非你认为她真的会
杀了你，
in which case, don't...
在这种情况下，不要...
..play dead, I mean.
..装死，我是说。
Right.
对。
Siegfried? Come now, Tristan.
齐格弗里德？来吧，特里斯坦。
It's alright to be frightened,
for without fear,
害怕也没关系，
因为没有恐惧，
there cannot be courage.
没有勇气。
Ha, without courage, there can't be
pain.
哈，没有勇气，就没有
痛苦。
# I'm called Little Buttercup
#我叫小毛毛
# Dear Little Buttercup. #
#亲爱的小毛茛。#
Try not to startle it!
尽量不要吓到它！
Forget the pig, you startled me!
忘记猪，你吓到我了！
Good Buttercup.
好的毛茛。
Good pig.
好猪。
BUTTERCUP GRUNTS
黄油杯咕噜声
Oh, God!
天啊！
BUTTERCUP GRUNTS
黄油杯咕噜声
Oh, ah.
哦，啊。
Mr Dinsdale, I fear we may have to
return with anaesthetic
丁斯代尔先生，我担心我们可能不得不
打麻药回来
to tame the beast before we operate.
在我们操作之前驯服野兽。
Oh, aye, when would that be then?
哦，是的，那会是什么时候？
Oh, not until this evening. What?
哦，直到今晚。什么？
No, Siegfried, we can't come back.
不，齐格弗里德，我们不能回来了。
Look, we're here now, I'll do it
now.
看，我们现在在这里，我
现在就去做。
He's either very brave or very
stupid.
他要么非常勇敢，要么非常
愚蠢。
I believe it's a heady mixture of
both.
我相信这是
两者的令人兴奋的混合。
No courage without fear.
没有恐惧就没有勇气。
BUTTERCUP GRUNTS
黄油杯咕噜声
Good God!
天哪！
I admire your persistence
佩服你的坚持
but sometimes discretion is
the better part of valour.
但有时谨慎是
勇气的更好部分。
He's done it.
他做到了。
I'll be damned.
我完蛋了。
I did?
我做的？
I mean, yes, I did.
我的意思是，是的，我做到了。
Yes, well, you made a bit of meal of
it but you got there in the end.
是的，好吧，你吃了
一点，但你最终到达了那里。
Maybe I'll, uh, see you later.
也许我会，呃，待会见。
Tristan, it's this way.
特里斯坦，就是这样。
Frowning at it won't change it.
皱眉不会改变它。
It's from a friend of my mum's.
是我妈妈的一个朋友寄来的。
He owns a vet's practice in Glasgow.
Hm.
他在格拉斯哥拥有一家兽医诊所。
嗯。
They've offered me a job.
他们给了我一份工作。
Well, I'm not surprised.
嗯，我并不感到惊讶。
Who wouldn't want you working for
them?
谁不想让你为
他们工作？
Mum seems to have accepted it for
me.
妈妈似乎已经为
我接受了。
Oh, dear.
哦亲爱的。
The practice is run by a man
called Bill Weipers.
该诊所由一位
名叫比尔·韦伯斯（Bill Weipers）的人经营。
He's on the board at Glasgow
Veterinary College.
他是格拉斯哥
兽医学院的董事会成员。
He employs modern methods
and equipment.
他采用现代方法
和设备。
He has an immaculate practice,
他有一个完美的练习，
sterile examination rooms, nurses,
无菌检查室、护士、
X-ray machine.
X光机。
And you got lumbered with us lot.
你和我们在一起很麻烦。
well, it's just a different...
嗯，这只是一个不同的......
..very different way of working.
..非常不同的工作方式。
If you ever have any ideas about how
如果你有任何想法
you might improve this place,
你可能会改善这个地方，
I'm sure Mr Farnon would hear you
out.
我相信法农先生会听到你的
。
If you catch him on a good day,
perhaps.
如果你在美好的一天抓住他，
也许。
It's more complicated than
that, Dad's struggling to get work.
比这更复杂
，爸爸正在努力找工作。
They're really struggling to
make ends meet.
他们真的在努力
维持生计。
Well, they'd want you to be happy.
好吧，他们希望你快乐。
As a parent, that's all you want for
your children.
作为父母，这就是您对
孩子的全部要求。
It feels so selfish.
感觉好自私啊
They spent their life savings
putting
他们用毕生积蓄
投入
me through college, I owe it to
them.
我通过大学，我欠
他们。
How long have you got to decide?
你需要多长时间做决定？
I've got a few months to work out
我有几个月的时间去锻炼
if there's something here worth
staying for.
如果这里有值得
停留的地方。
Or someone?
还是某人？
Helen took the other one.
海伦拿了另一个。
How many cases have we got to get
through this afternoon?
今天下午我们要处理多少案子？
16.
We'll use both examination rooms.
我们将使用两个考场。
While I'm treating an animal in
one...
当我在治疗一只动物时
...
I'll settle the next one into the
other room.
我会安排下一个到
另一个房间。
Once I've finished treatment, you
show them out, settle up the bill.
一旦我完成治疗，你
把他们展示出来，结账。
I'll go straight through to deal
with the next. Righto.
我会直接过去处理
下一个。对。
Hello, there.
你好呀。
Hello.
你好。
Good afternoon. Mr Herriot.
下午好。赫里奥特先生。
Afternoon. Hello.
下午。你好。
Right, Mrs Kirkby, with a rabbit.
对，柯克比夫人，带着一只兔子。
That's me.
这就是我。
Lovely.
迷人的。
Miss Fearnly? Yes, lovely.
费恩利小姐？是的，可爱。
Would you like to come through?
你想通过吗？
Thank you, Mrs Jackson.
谢谢你，杰克逊夫人。
Keep George warm by the fire,
that'll help speed up the waking
process.
让乔治在火边保持温暖，
这将有助于加快醒来的
过程。
Thank you, love.
谢谢你，爱。
It's Anne with Susie.
I'll be with you in a second.
是安妮和苏茜。
我一会就来陪你。
And don't you look happy about it.
你看起来不高兴吗。
Sorry, I've been rushed off my feet.
对不起，我已经被吓跑了。
Hello, Susie.
你好，苏茜。
How're you getting on with those
pups of yours?
你
和你的那些小狗相处得怎么样？
They're all grand.
他们都是伟大的。
First one you got out's
biggest of the lot.
第一个是你
最大的。
We named him James.
我们给他取名詹姆斯。
I'll have to come up and visit him.
我得上来拜访他。
Don't worry, Susie. Hey, we just
need to check how you're getting on.
别担心，苏茜。嘿，我们只
需要看看你过得怎么样。
BELL RINGS
铃响了
Excuse me. Come on through.
打扰一下。来吧。
Hi, Helen. Hi.
嗨，海伦。你好。
You look...
你看...
It's good to see you.
很高兴见到你。
Shall I come in?
我要进来吗？
Yes ,of course.
是的当然。
I'm just finishing up, I won't be
long, I swear.
我刚刚完成，我不会
太久，我发誓。
She won't mind waiting.
她不介意等待。
Oh, hello.
哦你好。
Tea? I think so.
茶？我想是这样。
Oh, you've certainly put
the weight back on.
哦，你肯定又把
重量放回去了。
Sorry, Susie.
对不起，苏茜。
That's very rude of me, isn't it?
这对我很粗鲁，不是吗？
You know, if ever you're to get
beyond smiling at the girl...
你知道，如果你要
超越对女孩的微笑......
..you might eventually have to do
something about it.
..你最终可能不得不为此做些
什么。
What happened to the other one?
What?
另一只怎么了？
什么？
I thought we could chat.
我以为我们可以聊天。
Um..
一..
..yeah, great, OK.
..是的，太好了，好的。
The other one, the barmaid,
Margaret?
另一个，酒保，
玛格丽特？
Maggie? I suppose she got sick of
you.
劣质煤？我猜她已经厌烦
你了。
Yeah, the thing about Maggie and me
is we're like ships in the night.
是的，关于玛吉和我的事情
是我们就像夜晚的船。
Travelling our own separate
courses...
旅行我们自己单独的
课程......
..occasionally we...
..偶尔我们...
..crash into one another during
stormy weather.
..在
暴风雨天气中相互碰撞。
Meanwhile, you happily flit...
与此同时，你快乐地飞过……
..courting one girl and then the
next.
..追求一个女孩，然后
下一个。
First of all - no-one courts.
首先- 没有人的法庭。
Then what are they doing?
They date.
那他们在做什么呢？
他们约会。
We're not Americans.
我们不是美国人。
The world's changing.
世界在变化。
Not every evening spent in the
company of a woman
不是每天晚上都在
女人的陪伴下度过
necessarily has to end in something
particularly meaningful.
必须以
特别有意义的事情结束。
In fact, most often it necessarily
doesn't.
事实上，大多数情况下不一定
。
Then what's the point of it all?
那么这一切的意义何在？
Fun.
乐趣。
I understand that's a very alien
concept to you.
我知道这
对你来说是一个非常陌生的概念。
I am fun, I'm perfectly bloody fun.
我很有趣，我非常有趣。
You certainly used to be.
你肯定曾经是。
Now I don't know what's happened.
What's that supposed to mean?
现在我不知道发生了什么。
那是什么意思？
You didn't used to be like this.
你以前不是这样的。
Like what?
像什么？
Allowing Merrick to get a free
ride...
让梅里克
搭便车……
..letting Pandhi rattle you and...
..让 Pandhi 让你和...
..don't even get me started on the
women.
..甚至不要让我开始谈论
女性。
Well, I imagine the problem's
getting you to stop.
好吧，我想问题是
让你停下来。
There's no spirit, the fight's gone.
没有精神，战斗就结束了。
I assure you, it has not.
Really?
我向你保证，它没有。
真的吗？
Cos in the not too distant past,
you would've tackled that sow
因为在不久的过去，
你会对付那头母猪
without a moment's hesitation,
毫不犹豫，
just to show people that you could.
只是为了向人们展示你可以。
I'm not saying you're past it but...
You just did!
我不是说你已经过去了，但是......
你刚刚做到了！
Stuck in a rut maybe, one that I
thought Dorothy
也许陷入了一种常规，我
认为多萝西
had got you out of it but...
已经让你摆脱它但是......
I'm not in a rut, there is no bloody
rut!
我没有在车辙，没有血腥的
车辙！
Oh, I'll get that for you.
哦，我给你拿。
Bye. Bye.
再见。再见。
Good evening, good evening, Mrs
Hall, Helen, a delight as ever.
晚上好，晚上好，
霍尔夫人，海伦，一如既往的快乐。
What happened to you?
你怎么了？
Fight with a pig.
与猪打架。
Is it hard to believe
I actually won?
很难相信
我真的赢了吗？
Bring your muddy things down,
把你的泥泞的东西放下，
don't leave them festering on the
floor.
不要让它们在
地板上溃烂。
It's been a long day.
这是漫长的一天。
You must barely recognise me.
你肯定差点没认出我来。
Oh, I don't know Siegfried,
哦，我不认识齐格弗里德，
I think you've weathered rather
well.
我认为你已经
过得很好。
You're very kind.
你好亲切。
How've you been?
最近怎么样？
You know, one foot in front of the
other.
你知道，一只脚在另一只脚前面
。
Glad to hear it.
听到那个消息很开心。
There you are, James.
你来了，詹姆斯。
About bloody time, poor Helen's
being bored silly waiting.
差不多该死的时候了，可怜的海伦
正在无聊地等待。
I'm fine, Mrs Hall's been looking
after me.
我很好，霍尔太太一直在照顾
我。
I had an emergency case,
我有一个紧急情况，
I've been playing catch up all day.
我一整天都在追赶。
You should really learn to deal
with these cases.
你真的应该学会处理
这些情况。
No wonder we're struggling
to turn a profit.
难怪我们正在努力
扭亏为盈。
I would say, Siegfried,
if Tristan were here today,
我会说，齐格弗里德，
如果特里斯坦今天在这里，
there would've been no need to
send anyone away.
没有必要
把任何人送走。
I want him with me until he's served
some time under my supervision.
我想让他和我在一起，直到他
在我的监督下服役一段时间。
He's more than capable.
他能力超群。
Oh, see how they shower me with
praise?
哦，看看他们如何
赞美我？
Perhaps this could wait for another
time?
也许这可以再等
一次？
No, if James has got something he
wants
不，如果詹姆斯有他
想要的东西
to get off his chest, I'd like to
hear it.
离开他的胸膛，我想
听听。
If Tristan were able to practise on
his own, we could take on more work.
如果特里斯坦能够自己练习
，我们可以承担更多的工作。
With the extra money, maybe we could
change a few things around here.
有了额外的钱，也许我们可以
改变这里的一些东西。
Change? Why on earth would
we want to change?
改变？
我们到底为什么要改变？
We could be working much more
efficiently,
我们可以更
有效地工作，
half of our equipment
is from the last century.
我们一半的设备
来自上个世纪。
So am I! Should we just toss me
out as well?
我也是！我们也应该把我扔
出去吗？
I don't think James means that.
我不认为詹姆斯是这个意思。
Of course I don't.
我当然不知道。
Siegfried, I learned more from you
in a year
齐格弗里德，
一年之内我从你身上学到了更多
than I did in all the time I spent
at college.
比我
在大学里度过的所有时间都多。
You flatter to deceive.
你受宠若惊。
It's true...
这是真的...
..he told me as much before.
..他以前也跟我说过。
I just want to be able to offer the
best care possible to our patients.
我只是希望能够
为我们的患者提供最好的护理。
Of course, as do I.
当然，我也是。
You know I'm always open to new
ideas.
你知道我总是乐于接受新
想法。
HE CHUCKLES
他笑了
What?
什么？
I am.
我是。
Did you know we were the first
practice in whole of Yorkshire
你知道我们是
整个约克郡的第一家诊所吗？
to have our own centrifuge for TB
testing?
拥有我们自己的离心机进行结核病
检测？
And I always put us forward
for the trial of new medications.
我总是建议我们
试用新药。
We are a forward looking practice.
我们是一个前瞻性的实践。
And I am one who always looks ahead,
rather than behind - always.
我是一个总是向前看，
而不是向后看的人——总是。
Semper progrediens!
一直在进步！
Always progressing. I know.
一直在进步。我知道。
Good. Well, that all seems settled
then.
好的。那么，一切似乎都解决了
。
Now, shouldn't you be going before
something or other
现在，你不应该在
某事或其他事情之前走吗？
turns into a pumpkin?
变成南瓜？
Semper progrediens!
一直在进步！
I believe he's fighting the
inevitable march of time.
我相信他正在与
不可避免的时间流逝作斗争。
Oh, Lord help us.
哦，求主帮助我们。
Go on, get on with you, I've my book
to read.
继续，继续，我有我的书
要读。
James...
詹姆士...
..good luck.
..祝你好运。
You sure you won't come?
你确定不来？
Oh, it's not for me.
哦，这不适合我。
Listen to that, Jess.
听着，杰斯。
Isn't that wonderful?
那是不是很美妙？
You'll be fine.
你会没事的。
Dorothy happen to mention
when she'll be returning?
多萝西碰巧提到
她什么时候回来？
She has no plans at the moment.
她目前没有任何计划。
Oh, and how do you feel about that?
哦，你怎么看？
How do I feel?
我感觉如何？
When you care about someone very
much, you...
当你很在乎一个人的
时候，你...
People have these things,
feelings, emotions.
人们有这些东西、
感觉、情绪。
Dorothy's a good friend - nothing
more.
多萝西是个好朋友——仅此而已
。
Understood.
明白了。
Well, then...
好吧...
..without fear...
……无所畏惧……
There can be no courage.
不可能没有勇气。
Once more unto the breach.
再一次突破。
Diana.
戴安娜。
Good evening. Good evening to
you.
晚上好。晚上好
。
You're looking stunning. Thank you.
你看起来很迷人。谢谢你。
How many do you think he'll
dance with tonight?
你认为他
今晚会和多少人跳舞？
I've a feeling that once she gets a
hold of him...
我有一种感觉，一旦她
抓住他...
..she won't be letting go.
..她不会放手的。
My mum used to make me
go to tea dances with her.
我妈妈过去常常让我
和她一起去跳茶舞。
It used to be me and a room full of
old ladies.
曾经是我和一个满屋子
老太太的房间。
Mum used to make me stand up in
front of all of them
妈妈曾经让我在
他们所有人面前站起来
and request songs from the singer.
并向歌手索取歌曲。
She didn't? I had to dance with
her...
她没有？我不得不和
她跳舞...
..and all her friends.
..还有她所有的朋友。
That's why I find it the most
embarrassing
所以我觉得最
尴尬
thing in the world to do.
世界上要做的事情。
It's probably why I'm terrible at
it.
这可能就是为什么我不擅长这个的原因
。
Oh, James, stop it.
哦，詹姆斯，别说了。
You're just saying it to make me
feel better.
你这么说只是为了让我
好受些。
So, I apologise in advance for the
absolute shambles
所以，我为
绝对的混乱提前道歉
this'll inevitably be
这将不可避免地
but would you like to dance?
但是你想跳舞吗？
I promise once people see me
out there,
我保证一旦人们看到我
在那里，
no-one is going to be talking
about your wedding with Hugh.
没有人会谈论
你和休的婚礼。
You'd really do that?
你真的会这样做吗？
You'd make a complete fool out of
yourself for me?
你会
为了我把自己变成一个彻头彻尾的傻瓜吗？
Every single day.
每一天。
No Maggie tonight, then?
那么今晚没有玛姬吗？
No, no, boyfriend. Her, not me.
不，不，男朋友。她，不是我。
That were very clever of you,
你真是太聪明了，
tricking that pig in to bursting its
own bubble.
诱使那头猪破灭它
自己的泡沫。
There'd be some who'd mistake
it for you running away.
有些人会误
以为你逃跑了。
Yes, well, it often takes brains
as well
是啊，它往往需要大脑
以及
as brawn to solve these problems.
作为解决这些问题的强者。
Hm, I'd settle for a pretty face.
嗯，我会满足于一张漂亮的脸蛋。
How about it, then?
那怎么办？
Oh, sadly, Anabel, I'm just not
one of life's dancers.
哦，可悲的是，安娜贝尔，我只是不是
生活中的舞者之一。
Oh, that's handy...
哦，这很方便...
..because I'm not one for dancing
either.
..因为我也不适合跳舞
。
Outstanding.
杰出的。
I've no idea what I'm doing.
我不知道我在做什么。
Don't worry, you're doing fine.
别担心，你做得很好。
Ooh. Sorry.
哦。对不起。
It's alright, I've got another one.
没关系，我还有一个。
Look, try and loosen up, let
yourself go with it.
看，试着放松，让
自己随心所欲。
That's it, that's better.
就是这样，这样更好。
Ooh!
哦！
That's a little too much.
这有点过分了。
I was sorry to hear about you
and your husband.
听到你
和你丈夫的事，我很难过。
Which was it, the housekeeper or the
gardener?
是管家还是
园丁？
Oh, I don't hold for such
tittle-tattle.
哦，我不喜欢这种
八卦。
Both, actually.
两者，实际上。
I wouldn't blame him if it was the
gardener - he was quite the dish.
如果是
园丁，我不会责怪他——他是个菜。
There's even one going round
甚至还有一轮
where I've got old Len buried in the
basement.
我把老伦埋在
地下室的地方。
That's why no-one's seen him
for so long.
这就是为什么
这么久没有人看到他的原因。
I don't mind that one so much,
我不太介意那个，
it keeps everybody on their toes.
它让每个人都保持警觉。
Farnon, we've got ourselves a bit of
a problem.
法农，我们自己有点
问题。
Yes, Colonel, I believe we have.
是的，上校，我相信我们有。
I was in the middle of a charming
conversation with
我正在
与
this young lady and I've been rudely
interrupted.
这位小姐和我被粗鲁地
打断了。
I beg your pardon?
请再说一遍？
You can beg all you like,
you're not having it.
你可以随心所欲地乞求，
但你没有得到。
Now, if you'll excuse me.
现在，如果你能原谅我。
You see, Colonel, what did I tell
you?
你看，上校，我跟
你说了什么？
He's lost it.
他失去了它。
I do apologise, Diana.
我真的很抱歉，戴安娜。
Oh, no need.
哦，没必要。
I love a bit of drama.
我喜欢一点戏剧。
Now hear this, Farnon, that cow is
still unwell.
现在听到这个，法农，那头牛
仍然不舒服。
You told me it needed an operation.
你告诉我它需要手术。
If you're not willing to come up
and sort her...
如果你不愿意上来给
她分类……
..well, I can always take my custom
elsewhere.
..好吧，我总是可以
在别处采取我的习惯。
Custom suggests a transfer of money
for services rendered.
海关建议
为提供的服务转移资金。
I put a lot of work your way.
我按照你的方式做了很多工作。
Because we're the finest in the
district.
因为我们是这个地区最好的
。
We've three qualified vets and
enough work
我们有三名合格的兽医和
足够的工作
to necessitate the expansion of our
practice.
有必要扩大我们的
实践。
We don't have to fight like jackals
over scraps left by others.
我们不必像豺狼一样
为别人留下的碎片而战。
If you really want the best possible
care for your animals,
如果您真的想
为您的动物提供最好的照顾，
you can call during our normal
business hours.
您可以在我们正常
工作时间内致电。
Otherwise, go with the reserve team.
否则，去预备队。
Good evening.
晚上好。
Good evening? I'll give you good
evening!
晚上好？我给你说
晚安！
That was very impressive.
Thank you.
那是非常令人印象深刻的。
谢谢你。
Where are we going?
我们去哪？
No idea, I always like to sweep
out at the end of an argument.
不知道，我总是喜欢
在争论结束时扫地。
But since we're on the move, might I
suggest somewhere more salubrious?
但既然我们在移动，我可以
建议一个更有益的地方吗？
The Renniston, perhaps? Why not?
也许是雷尼斯顿？为什么不？
Sorry again about your toes.
再次为你的脚趾感到抱歉。
Oh, it was great.
哦，太棒了。
You were great.
你很棒。
It's been so long since...
过了这么久...
I really needed that.
我真的需要那个。
I'm glad.
我很高兴。
I'll, er, I'll fetch our drinks.
我去，呃，我去拿我们的饮料。
Don't forget to come up for air.
别忘了上来呼吸一下。
Goodnight, Tristan.
晚安，特里斯坦。
Helen, been awhile. How've you been?
海伦，好久不见。最近怎么样？
Yeah, not bad. You?
是的，还不错。你？
Oh, same as always...
哦，一如既往...
What do you say then, lass,
Fancy a turn around the floor?
那你怎么说，姑娘，想
在地板上转一圈吗？
Oh, Fernley, this is... Hello.
哦，芬利，这是……你好。
I'm James Herriot.
我是詹姆斯·赫里奥特。
Right, nice.
对，不错。
I'm sorry.
抱歉。
I didn't mean to... If you two are
together, then.
我不是故意的……如果你们两个
在一起，那么。
Us? Oh, no, we're not.
我们？哦，不，我们不是。
Are we? No, not at all.
我们是吗？一点都不。
Only, we were known to have the odd
dance in the past.
只是，我们知道
过去有奇怪的舞蹈。
We even won a show together.
我们甚至一起赢得了一场表演。
Go on, at least he won't stand on
your toes.
继续，至少他不会站在
你的脚趾上。
Right.
对。
Really, no trouble.
真的，没毛病。
Enjoy yourself.
玩的开心。
Thanks, James.
谢谢，詹姆斯。
Idiot.
笨蛋。
Tea, Siegfried?
茶，齐格弗里德？
If you wouldn't mind, Tristan,
如果你不介意，特里斯坦，
thank you, very kind.
谢谢，很亲切。
When. Bless you.
什么时候。祝福你。
Good evening? Oh, very much so.
晚上好？哦，非常如此。
How long's this going to go on for?
What?
这要持续多久？
什么？
The inane expressions...
无语的表情...
..the smug sense of satisfaction.
..自鸣得意的满足感。
Mrs Hall, I would've thought
you'd be glad
霍尔夫人，我以为
你会很高兴
to hear we enjoyed ourselves last
night.
听说我们
昨晚玩得很开心。
Oh, it's enough to put me off my
breakfast.
哦，这足以让我
不吃早餐了。
What about James?
詹姆斯呢？
Did he enjoy himself?
他自己玩得开心吗？
PHONE RINGS
电话铃声
Darrowby, two, two, nine, seven.
达罗比，二，二，九，七。
One moment.
一会。
Mr Farnon.
法农先生。
Colonel Merrick.
梅里克上校。
Yes, what, is it?
是的，这是什么？
Oh, you do?
哦，你呢？
Yes, well, I'll have to consult our
appointment diary first.
是的，好吧，我得先查阅一下我们的
约会日记。
Three o'clock?
三点钟？
Breakfast's on the table.
早餐在桌上。
I'll be there in a minute.
我马上就到。
SIEGFRIED: See you then.
西格瑞德：到时候见。
How'd it go?
过得怎么样？
He's doing all right, temperature's
down.
他一切正常，温度
下降了。
The infection is starting
to clear up.
感染开始
好转。
You can call Mr Hammond and tell him
to pick him up later.
你可以打电话给哈蒙德先生，让他
稍后来接他。
That's not what I meant.
那并非我的本意。
Oh, love.
哦，爱。
It's alright.
没关系。
There are a lot of people Helen
needs to catch up with.
海伦
需要赶上很多人。
SIEGFRIED: Herriot!
西格瑞德：赫里奥特！
Tristan!
特里斯坦！
I'm literally three feet away from
you.
我真的离
你三英尺远。
I don't understand why you
have to bellow.
我不明白你为什么
要吼叫。
Don't be such a sensitive Sidney.
Here.
不要这么敏感的西德尼。
这里。
I've been keeping these back, one
each.
我一直在保留这些，一个
一个。
And what are these for?
而这些是干什么用的？
You said you wanted us to modernise,
James?
你说你想让我们现代化，
詹姆斯？
We're about to give the good Colonel
a show he'll never forget.
我们要给这位优秀的上校
表演一场他永远不会忘记的表演。
Morning, Colonel.
早上好，上校。
No Pandhi today?
今天没有潘迪？
You're our vet, Farnon, for now, at
any rate.
无论如何，你现在是我们的兽医，法农。
Well, I'm glad we managed to squeeze
you in.
好吧，我很高兴我们能把
你挤进去。
Yes, prepare the patient
for the operation.
是的，让患者做好手术准备
。
COW MOOS
牛摩丝
Thank you.
谢谢你。
Right. This is where we go in.
对。这是我们进去的地方。
I hope you aren't squeamish,
it's not for the faint hearted.
我希望你不要娇气，
这不适合胆小的人。
I've seen blood before, you needn't
worry, I shan't faint.
我以前见过血，你不用
担心，我不会晕倒的。
Now, you see the rumen exposed,
the cow's first stomach,
现在，你看到瘤胃暴露了，
牛的第一个胃，
you know they have four?
你知道他们有四个吗？
Hang on Farnon, that doesn't look
too clever.
等等 Farnon，这看起来
不太聪明。
Um, yes, it's probably just
a bit of ruminal gas.
嗯，是的，它可能只是
一点瘤胃气体。
Wouldn't you say?
你不说吗？
Aye, probably.
是的，大概。
James, could I borrow you for a
second?
詹姆斯，我能借你一下
吗？
Farnon, what was it you said,
the finest vet in the district?
法农，你说什么，
区里最好的兽医？
You're putting on a right show, now.
你现在正在上一场正确的表演。
Siegfried, do you not think
the good Colonel could
齐格弗里德，你认为
好上校不会
benefit from seeing some of your
handiwork up close?
从
近距离观看您的一些手工艺品中受益？
You know, you really are full
of good ideas at the moment, James.
你知道吗
，詹姆斯，你现在真的满脑子都是好主意。
Yes, Colonel, come in.
是的，上校，进来。
Come in, that's it.
进来，就这样。
That's it, a little closer.
就这样，再近一点。
Scalpel, please.
请用手术刀。
There we are. Thank you.
我们到了。谢谢你。
Ready, Colonel?
准备好了吗，上校？
Oh, get on with it, Farnon.
哦，继续吧，法农。
Oh, oh.
哦，哦。
COLONEL MERRICK: Absolutely...
梅里克上校：绝对……
That's what the problem was. What do
you make of that?
这就是问题所在。你怎么看
？
Farnon, what the...
It's Mr Farnon...
法农，这是什么……
法农先生……
..and my bill will be in the post.
..我的帐单会在邮局里。
Well, I thought that went rather
well. Mm.
好吧，我认为这进行得相当
顺利。毫米。
Absolutely. Quite the show.
Text book.
绝对地。相当的表演。
课本。
COLONEL MERRICK: God, absolutely
covered in the stuff.
梅里克上校：天啊，完全
被这些东西覆盖了。
You'll have to keep him inside for a
few days
你得把他关在里面
几天
to keep the wound clean.
以保持伤口清洁。
But I'm pleased with how the
infection is clearing up.
但我对
感染的清除情况感到满意。
Well, we can't thank you enough,
Mr Herriot.
好吧，我们对你的感激不尽，
赫里奥特先生。
No trouble at all.
一点都不麻烦。
Mrs Hall will show you out.
霍尔太太会带你出去的。
Come on, then, Rock, here we go.
来吧，Rock，我们开始吧。
It looks like these two have
become firm friends.
看来两人已经
成为了好朋友。
Oh, we'll be sorry to see him go.
Won't we, Jess?
哦，我们会很遗憾看到他离开。
我们不会吗，杰斯？
I'm sure they could see each other
again.
我相信他们可以
再次见面。
We could take them for a walk
together.
我们可以带他们
一起散步。
One of the men usually take Jess
out.
其中一名男子通常会带杰斯
出去。
Ah, well, never mind.
啊，好吧，别介意。
Maybe we'll see you out
and about, hey, Jess.
也许我们会在外面见你
，嘿，杰斯。
When you grow tired of moving
your clock forward,
当你厌倦了
让时钟向前移动时，
let me know and I'll come fix it.
让我知道，我会来解决它。
Lost time is never found again.
失去的时间再也找不回来了。
Come on, Rock, let's go.
来吧，洛克，我们走吧。
Oh, hold on.
哦，等一下。
Oh, Helen, love, good to see you.
哦，海伦，亲爱的，很高兴见到你。
Is James about?
詹姆斯约吗？
In there.
在那里。
Come in.
进来吧。
I'm just clearing up, won't be a
second.
我正在清理，不会一
秒钟。
Sorry we lost each other last night.
对不起，我们昨晚失去了彼此。
Oh, it's fine, don't worry.
哦，没关系，别担心。
It's been so long since I caught up
with everyone.
我已经很久没有赶上
大家了。
I've known most of them since we
were kids.
我从小就认识他们中的大多数
。
Oh, it's all right, I understand.
哦，没关系，我明白了。
It was the same for me when I went
home, seeing everyone again.
当我
回到家时，我也是如此，再次见到大家。
It feels strange hearing you call
somewhere else home.
听到你打电话给
别处的家感觉很奇怪。
You belong here.
你属于这里。
This is your home.
这是你的家。
I looked for you last night,
couldn't find you?
昨晚
找你了，没找到？
I got dragged into a conversation
outside
我被拖进了
外面的谈话
with Gene Gilbert and
Mr Summers.
吉恩·吉尔伯特和
萨默斯先生。
Once they get their teeth in,
they're hard to shake off.
一旦他们咬牙切齿，
就很难摆脱。
I would've liked to have danced with
you again.
我很想
再和你跳舞。
If your toes could take it.
如果你的脚趾可以承受。
Last night were the first time in a
long time
昨晚是
很久以来的第一次
that I've felt like myself again...
我又感觉像我自己了……
..and I was only there because of
you.
..而我只是因为
你而在那里。
Everything all right with
Miss Alderson?
奥尔德森小姐一切都好吗？
Aye, grand.
是的，伟大的。
Everything's grand.
一切都是伟大的。